

MELHEM EL DIRANI

WEB DEVELOPER / ENTREPRENEUR

+961-71-523153 melhemdirani@hotmail.com

melhemdirani.github.io/Melhem/

Saida, Lebanon



PROFILE ME

An experienced self-taught web developer. Having owned and developed an online digital agency that provides web based services like web development and web design. Expertise in developing, testing and maintaining web applications using html, css, javascript and other frameworks and libraries like react, redux and nodejs. Known for being a cheerful, caring, practical, motivational and commercially minded team-player. A lover of life and people, aiming to create a healthy work environment and help others growing their skills.

EXPERIENCE

2021 - present

Reboost

Lebanon

WEB DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEADER / CEO

- Designing, building and configuring applications to meet business process and application requirements
- Directing the development team in the design, development, coding, testing and debugging of applications
- Writing testable, scalable and efficient code and leading code reviews
- Mentoring junior team members and ensuring they adhere to determined software quality standards
- Planning and documenting technical specifications for features or system design

2021 -2022

Self employed

Remotely

WEB DEVELOPMENT TEACHER

- Guide and assist fresh students in their study plan.
- Teach new concepts, languages and frameworks.
- Provide students with relevant resources to help them grow their skills and reach their goals.

2021 - 2021

Sicilia Mia

Italy

INTERN FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER, SICILIA MIA

- Reviewing application requirements and interface designs.
 Developing and implementing highly-responsive user interface components using React concepts.
- Writing application interface codes using JavaScript following React.js workflows and frameworks like Redux. Troubleshooting interface software and debugging application codes.
- Developing and implementing front-end architecture to support user interface concepts.
- Monitoring and improving front-end performance.

EDUCATION

2016 -2018

Rafik Hariri University Mechref, Lebanon MASTER DEGREE IN CIVIL ENGINEERING Web Development

Leadership

SKILLS

Problem Solving

Communication

2015 -2019

Lebanese University Saida, Lebanon BACHELOR DEGREE IN CIVIL ENGINEERING